Finding aid to the Margaret Mahoney papers SSC.MS.00230
Sophia Smith Collection
Margaret E. Mahoney papers
1924-2012
Sophia Smith Collection
Mahoney, Margaret E.
SSC.MS.00230
30.5 linear feet (73 boxes)
Margaret Ellerbe Mahoney papers primarily document Mahoney's professional activities. Her service on the boards of numerous education and medical foundations, her teaching at Princeton University, and her grant writing are notable accomplishments. Types of material include biographical material, correspondence, business and financial records, fundraising records, committee and conference files, appointment books, reports, speeches and lecture notes, photographs, and videotapes.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was donated to the archives by Margaret Mahoney in 11 installments from 1987-2013.
Appraisal
Some of Margaret Mahoney's papers were previously housed at the Rockefeller Archive Center in New York. Margaret Mahoney sent financial materials related to her organization, MEM Associates in 2005, 2006, and 2007. They identified that these materials should be destroyed after 7 years, respectively. This was completed by the processors of the papers. Other materials that were sent by Margaret Mahoney yet were unrelated to her or her mother's papers, were deaccessioned including Civil War-era newspapers entitled, War of the Rebellion.
Margaret Mahoney agreed to donate two books, Marmaduke Multiply and Lady Chatterley's Lover to Smith College's Mortimer Rare Book Collection as they did not fit the scope of the Sophia Smith Collection's collection policy; they were acquired in 2002.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into 8 series:
Biographical
Correspondence
Employment
Organizations
Photographs
Speeches and Writings
Subject Files
Restricted Materials
Biographical / Historical
Margaret Ellerbe Mahoney was best known as a philanthropist, executive of many non-profit organizations, civic leader, and trustee of Smith College. The papers primarily document Margaret Mahoney's philanthropic work with the Carnegie Corporation of New York, the Robert Wood Johnson Foundation, The Commonwealth Fund, UNESCO, and her consulting firm specializing in health care delivery systems, MEM Associates, Inc. The papers also document Margaret Mahoney's personal life, mainly through correspondence.
Margaret Ellerbe Mahoney was born in Nashville, Tennessee on October 24, 1924. Her parents, Charles Hallam Mahoney and Leslie Nelson (Nell) Savage Mahoney, had a brief marriage that ended in divorce in May 1925. Leslie Mahoney received full custody of Margaret. Charles Mahoney would later marry a woman named Elizabeth Wood. Charles Mahoney's family did not recognize Margaret's existence, and Margaret had no contact with them until a cousin, Joan Cooper, wrote her, months before Charles's death on August 20, 1988.
Margaret's mother, Leslie Mahoney, was an interior design expert and received a Master of Arts in history for her thesis titled "The Building of the Tennessee State House, 1845-1854." Many of Margaret's other relatives worked as doctors at Vanderbilt University. Her maternal grandfather, Dr. Giles C. Savage, and aunt, Dr. Kate Eastman Savage Zerfoss, shared an ophthalmology practice in Nashville, Tennessee, at what was then known as the Savage House. The Savage House was one of only two Nashville townhouses to survive the Civil War and is now listed on the National Register of Historic Places. Dr. Kate Zerfoss advocated for the addition of white lines to the edges of roads as a safety measure.
Margaret Mahoney attended Ward Belmont and West End High School, graduating from the latter in 1942. She attended Vanderbilt University and received a Bachelor of Arts degree in international relations with dual minors in history and art in 1946. Her college years were interrupted by wartime service. She briefly served on a classified assignment with the Army Signal Corps in Arlington, Virginia in 1944.
After her graduation from Vanderbilt, she returned to Washington, D.C. area to join the United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) Relations Staff at the Department of State, arriving in time for the First Session of the General Conference of UNESCO. She began as a clerk-typist and rose to become a program officer for cultural affairs. Her positions at UNESCO sent her traveling to Mexico and Lebanon, among other places. She initiated and organized the International Theatre Institute, the International Association of the Plastic Arts, and the International Music Council.
She continued her interest in arts programming after she left UNESCO in 1953 for the Carnegie Corporation in New York City. The Carnegie Corporation introduced her to grant-making, which she continued with for the rest of her professional career. Toward the end of Margaret Mahoney's tenure at Carnegie, she transitioned away from arts-focused philanthropy and instead into the realm of healthcare philanthropy.
In 1972, she accepted the position of vice president of the Robert Wood Johnson Foundation (RWJF), where she was able to continue working on grants focused on improving quality and access to healthcare. From 1975-1979, during her tenure at RWJF, she was on the faculty of the Princeton University Program in Science and Human Affairs. She taught a course titled "Medicine in Modern America" at Princeton University.
In 1980, she moved back to New York City full-time in order to become president of the Commonwealth Fund, making her the first woman to head a major American foundation. She serves as president of the Commonwealth Fund from 1980-1984.
Margaret Mahoney founded MEM Associates, Inc., a not-for-profit consulting firm specializing in health care delivery systems. The MEM Associates, inc. organization was headquartered in New York City in 1995. A major initiative of MEM Associates, Inc. was the Healthy Steps for Young Children Program. This program sought to improve the care and education for children ages 0-3. MEM Associates, Inc. also advised other non-profit organizations on developing fundable initiatives to advance the health and well-being of the American public.
Margaret Mahoney served on a variety of boards and educational foundations including the U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare's Medical Assistance Advisory Council; the Task Force on Medicaid and Related Programs; the Health Industry Advisory Committee of the Cost of Living Council; the Dermatology Foundation; the Sun Valley Forum on National Health; the National Humanities Center; and the Smith College Board of Trustees (1988-93). A copy of Margaret Mahoney's professional chronology can be found in the control file.
Margaret Mahoney received many awards and honors for her professional dedication between 1970 -2011, including numerous honorary degrees and the Lahey Award from the National Fund for Medical Education. After years of failing health, Margaret Mahoney died in New York City on December 22, 2011.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
As a preservation measure, researchers must use digital copies of audiovisual materials in this collection. Please consult with Special Collections staff to request the creation of and access to digital copies.
Related Materials
Related material can be found in the Leslie Nelson Savage Mahoney papers in the Sophia Smith Collection.
Further information about Margaret's professional work can be found in multiple places:
the Carnegie Corporation's archives are housed at Columbia University's Rare Book and Manuscript Library
the records of the Commonwealth Fund, including material related to Margaret Mahoney's tenure as President, are housed at the Rockefeller Archive Center
the Trinity Church Parish Archive holds material related to Mahoney's service on the Board of Trustees and Grants Board of the Church
Scope and Contents
The Margaret Ellerbe Mahoney papers consists of 30.5 linear feet of printed materials, such as diaries, calendars, speeches, photographs, clippings, minutes, memoranda, itineraries, and correspondence; and audio-visual materials, such as VHS tapes, audiotapes, and one floppy disk. The papers document Margaret's life from childhood until her death in 2011.
Documents that represent Mahoney's personal life can be found in Biographical Material and Correspondence series. The bulk of the printed material document Margaret's professional life and activities. Significant quantities of the collection represent information on philanthropic foundations, particularly those based in New York and pertaining to healthcare grantmaking.
Mahoney, Margaret E.; Mahoney, Leslie Nelson Savage; Carnegie Corporation of New York; Commonwealth Fund; Fund raising; Interior decorators--United States--Biography; Arts fund raising; Europe--Description and travel; Medical care--United States; Philanthropists--United States; Public health--Research--United States; Architecture--United States--History; Architecture, Domestic--Tennessee; Women philanthropists; Women in the professions--United States; Mahoney, Leslie Nelson Savage (Nell Savage Mahoney); Mahoney family; Carnegie Corporation of New York--History--Sources; Commonwealth Fund--History--Sources; Mahoney, Leslie Nelson Savage (Nell Savage Mahoney); Mahoney, Margaret E.
- Biographical materials, 1924-2012; 1; 4.5 linear feet (11 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series provides an overview of the personal life of Margaret Mahoney. It includes a wide range of materials that document Mahoney's childhood to adulthood including clippings, educational items, familial history papers, financial documents, household documents, interviews with Margaret Mahoney, social events, and travel itineraries.
  Of note, there is a World War II ration book, appointment books document Mahoney's daily schedule; awards and honors; a baby book that contains early photographs of her and her family; materials from class notes and papers from elementary school through her time at Vanderbilt University; material about Margaret Mahoney's mother, Leslie Nelson (Nell) Savage Mahoney's work as an interior designer; financial documents that provide researchers with a sense of Mahoney's expenses, charitable contributions, and income; information about Mahoney's real estate activities; and travel materials from Maine, England, Ireland, and Egypt.
  Related Materials
  Additional information about Margaret Mahoney's family can be found within Series 2. Correspondence and about Margaret Mahoney's travel in Series 3. Employment.
  - Margaret Mahoney biographical sketches/resumes, 1951-2012 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Books dedicated to or mentioning Margaret Mahoney, approximately 1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Christ Church, 1924-1953 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Christmas, 1975-1993 (Box 1, Folder 4-11)
  - Memorabilia, 1932-1956 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Memorial service, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
  - Miscellaneous notes, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Political activities: Marjorie Powell Allen campaign, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Portrait, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Quote book, 1959-1970 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Telephone call log, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 19-24)
  - Address books, 1935-2005 (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
  - Margaret Mahoney appointment books and calendars, 1971-2001 (Box 2, Folder 6-20)
  - Margaret Mahoney appointment books and calendars, 1971-2001 (Box 3, Folder 1-16)
  - Margaret Mahoney appointment books and calendars, 1971-2001 (Box 4, Folder 1-22)
  - Margaret Mahoney appointment books and calendars, 1971-2001 (Box 5, Folder 1-7)
  - General awards and honors, 1970-2011 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - "Achievements and Accomplishments" (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Academy for Educational Development, "Woman of Valor", 2006 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Beaver College honorary degree, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Brandeis University honorary degree, 21 May 1989; 1 folders (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - Brandeis University honorary degree, 1989-1994; 1 folders (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Medical College of Pennsylvania honorary degree, 1982; 1 folders (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - The Medical College of Pennsylvania newspaper, Spring, 1982; 1 folders (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Meharry Medical College honorary degree, 1995; 1 folders (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - New York Medical College honorary degree, 1995; 1 folders (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Smith College honorary degree, 1984-1985; 1 folders (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - University of Florida honorary degree, 1980; 1 folders (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Williams College honorary degree, 1983; 1 folders (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Margaret Mahoney accolades, 1993-1998; 1 folders (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - MEM Accolades, Poster, Lotos Club State dinner in honor of MEM, 18 April 1994; 1 folders (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - MEM Accolades, "Execs' Brush with Destiny," Crain's New York Business, 08 Feb 1999; 1 folders (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - National Fund for Medical Education: Lahey Award correspondence, general, guest list, speech, 1984-1985; 7 folders (Box 5, Folder 20-26)
  - New York Academy of Medicine, "Margaret Mahoney: Fourteen Years of Creative Leadership", 1994; 1 folders (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - New York Academy of Medicine, Associate Fellowship, 27 Jan 1982; 1 folders (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - New York Academy of Medicine, Fellowship, 27 Jan 1982; 1 folders (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - New York Academy of Medicine, First Annual Margaret E. Mahoney Lecture and Symposium on the State of the Nation's Health, program, 22 May 1995; 1 folders (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - Secretary's Unit Citation for outstanding contribution to the Task Force on Medicaid and Related Programs, August 1970; 1 folders (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - New York Academy of Medicine, Mahoney Symposium, 1995-1995 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Women's Forum, Inc., 1989 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Margaret Mahoney Baby books, 1924-1937 (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
  - Camp Nakanawa, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Early drawings, approximately 1924-1944 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Margarey Mahoney, Writing, "The Door to Poetry,", 1925 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Margaret Mahoney, Writing, Story book, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Margaret Mahoney, Writing, Spelling book, approximately 1934 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Margaret Mahoney, Writing, Notebook, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Margaret Mahoney, Writing, "The Party", 1941 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, General, 1942-1995 (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
  - Clippings, Monteagle, Tennessee, 1940-1942 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, Profile in Town and Country, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Clippings, "Koussevitsky: Missing in Action," Los Angeles Times, 18 Dec 1983; 1 items (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, "My Hero: AJ Ayer on Albert Einstein," The Independent Magazine, 2 Sep 1989; 1 items (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - Margaret Mahoney education, Certificate of Promotion, First Baptist Sunday School, 24 Sep 1933; 1 items (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - Education, Drawing pad, English, History/Geography, Italian, Themes, approximately 1924-2012 (Box 6, Folder 17-22)
  - Education, Peabody Demonstration School, 1935-1936 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Education, Ward-Belmont School, record, diploma, and history notebook, 1934-1942 (Box 6, Folder 24-25)
  - Margaret Mahoney education, Ward-Belmont May Festival programs, 1937-1938; 1 folders (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - Margaret Mahoney education, Parmer School certificate, May 13, 1938; 1 folders (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - Education, Parmer school, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Education, Cavert Junior High, 1938-1939 (Box 7, Folder 2-3)
  - Education, West End High School, diploma, record, Chemistry, English, History, Latin, 1939-1942 (Box 7, Folder 4-17)
  - Margaret Mahoney education, The West Wind, West End High School, April-May 1942; 1 items (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - Education, Vanderbilt University, bound notes, papers, 1944-1946 (Box 7, Folder 19-35)
  - Education, Vanderbilt University, bound notes, papers, 1944-1946 (Box 8, Folder 1-5)
  - Family, Joan Cooper, 1988-1999 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Family, Martha Leslie Dubose, 1993-1997 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Family, Ellerbe and Prince families, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 8-9)
  - Family, "The First 175 Years at Ellerbe Springs,", 1995 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Family, Charles Hallam Mahoney, 1974-2001 (Box 8, Folder 11-12)
  - Family, Nell Savage Mahoney, General, 1983-1988 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Family, Nell Savage Mahoney, Legal and financial matters, General, 1980-1984 (Box 8, Folder 14-15)
  - Family, Nell Savage Mahoney, "Mother,", 1997-2005 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Family, Nell Savage Mahoney, Tennessee Historical Society, 1983-1988 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Family, Nell Savage Mahoney, Tennessee State Museum, 1981-1983 (Box 8, Folder 18-19)
  - Family, Leslie Prince Raimond, 1999-2005 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Family, Prince family, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Family tree of Samuel Earnest Zerfoss, approximately 1924-2007; 1 items (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence from Thomas B. Zerfoss and Evelyn Zerfoss, 2004-2007; 1 items (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - Family, Savage-Zerfoss family, General, 1966-2007 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Family, Sacage-Zerfoss family, Elizabeth Zerfoss Fryer, 1930-1982 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Family, Savage-Zerfoss family, Kate Savage Zerfoss correspondence, 1930-1982 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Family, Savage-Zerfoss family, Thomas B. Zerfoss, II, 1991-2008 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Margaret Mahoney charitable contributions, 1985-2009 (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
  - Margaret Mahoney expenses and income, 1977-1979 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Expenses of Nell Savage Mahoney, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Finances, General, 1942-1995 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Margaret Mahoney household employers tax, 1976-1988 (Box 9, Folder 8-10)
  - Margaret Mahoney income other than as author, income as author, 1969-1974 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Margaret Mahoney Department of Health, Education and Welfare Taskforce on Medicaid and Related Programs, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Margaret Mahoney tax, 1980-1986 (Box 9, Folder 13-14)
  - Margaret Mahoney insurance, 1952-1984 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Margaret Mahoney loans, 1951-1958 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Margaret Mahoney trust, 1986-1989 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Margaret Mahoney apartment rentals, 1949-1970 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Margaret Mahoney Edgewood apartment, general, financial statements, purchase, 1980-1984 (Box 9, Folder 19-23)
  - Nashville Interiors: 1866 to 1920 signed by Amelia Edwards, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Apartments, New York realtors, 1983-1985 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Apartments, Princeton, New Jersey house (243 Hamilton), burglary, inventories, purchase, sale, relocation, 1972-1980 (Box 10, Folder 3-9)
  - Apartments, Waller separation, Correspondence, photographs, general, 1968-1979 (Box 10, Folder 10-14)
  - Waller separation, approximately 1968-1979; 15 min. Norelco mini-cassette (Box 71, Folder 12)
  - Waller separation, approximately 1968-1979; 1/4 Norelco audio tape (Box 71, Folder 13)
  - Apartments, Leases for Manhattan apartments, 225 East 57th Street, 1967-1970; 1 items (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - Apartments, Leases for Manhattan apartments, 320 East 50th Street, 1962-1963; 1 items (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - Household, Map of McLean Gardens residence halls, approximately 1944; 1 items (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - Interview with Margaret Mahoney, 1981; 1 items (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - Interview with Margaret Mahoney, Claremont University, 13 April 1994 (Box 71, Folder 15)
  - Interviews with Margaret Mahoney, Meharry Medical College, 09 Oct 2003 (Box 71, Folder 16)
  - Interviews with Margaret Mahoney, National Library of Medicine, 01 July 2003 (Box 71, Folder 17)
  - Interviews with Margaret Mahoney, Carol A. Mockvos, University of Chicago, "Creativity in Later Life", 13 Apr 1994; T-120 VHS (Box 71, Box 4)
  - Social events, Lucy Howorth award, 28 Oct 1983 (Box 71, Folder 18)
  - Social events, dinners, 1983-1990 (Box 71, Folder 19)
  - Social events, Fifth annual Alfred E. Smith Memorial Foundation dinner, 19 Oct 1995 (Box 71, Folder 20, Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - Social events, Miscellaneous, 1995-1997 (Box 71, Folder 21)
  - Social events, Eightieth birthday party, 24 Oct 2004 (Box 71, Folder 22)
  - Events, AAMC Award Presentation, 30 Oct 1994; T-120 VHS (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Travel, Aboard the Queen Mary, 01-06 Jan 1949 (Box 71, Folder 23)
  - Travel, Clashleigh House, Ireland, August 1989 (Box 71, Folder 24)
  - Travel, Egypt, approximately 1924-2012 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
  - Travel, England with Greg and Mary McNeill, April 1987 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Travel, Itineraries, 1980-1995 (Box 11, Folder 4-17)
  - Travel, Maine, approximately 1924-2012 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Travel, "Amid Cairo's Clamor, Pathways Old and New," New York Times, 1 Jan 1989; 1 items (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - Travel, Map of Luxor, 1988; 1 items (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - Travel, Annotated map of Great Britain and Ireland, approximately 1924-2007; 1 items (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1932-2011; 2; 7.5 linear feet (18 boxes)
  This series is arranged into two sub-series, Personal and Professional.
  The Personal sub-series is arranged into alphabetical, chronological, and subject-specific correspondence. Mahoney's most prolific correspondent was her mother, Leslie Nelson (Nell) Savage Mahoney, whom she often addressed as "Duchess" or "Lady." Margaret Mahoney also exchanged a substantial amount of correspondence with Thelma Ingles, a healthcare professional, whose papers can be found at Duke University Medical Center Archives, and with Edward Staempfli, a Swiss musical composer and paramour of Mahoney.
  The Professional sub-series is further arranged into General and Outgoing correspondence. General correspondence dates from 1992-1998 and is arranged alphabetically. Outgoing correspondence dates from 1978-2007 and is arranged chronologically.
  - Personal, alphabetical, Jean Bradford, 1954-1968 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Personal, alphabetical, Mary Caldwell, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Personal, alphabetical, Karen Davis, 1992-1996 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Personal, alphabetical, Fred, 1950s; 1 folders (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Personal, alphabetical, Thelma Ingles, 1972-1984 (Box 11, Folder 23-26, Box 12, Folder 1-3)
  - Personal, alphabetical, Theodore Katz, 1989-2007 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Personal, alphabetical, Theodore Katz, including pencil portrait, 7 April 1985 (Mapcase 52, Folder 1)
  - Personal, alphabetical, Lt. Tom Kelly, Aug 1944-Nov 1945 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Personal, alphabetical, Nell Savage Mahoney, 1932-1969 (Box 12, Folder 6-18, Box 13, Folder 1-14, Box 14, Box 1-9)
  - Personal, alphabetical, Nancy, 1943-1946 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Personal, alphabetical, Sadako Nakamura, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Personal, alphabetical, Barbara Pasquito, 1981-1993 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Personal, alphabetical, Kanta Reddy, 1964-2006 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Personal, alphabetical, G. William Sattler, III, 1946-1947 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Personal, alphabetical, Dorothy Saunders, 1980-1985 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Personal, alphabetical, Pfc. Theodore C. Snyder, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Personal, alphabetical, Sophia Smith Collection and Smith College, 1985-2009 (Box 15, Folder 4-7)
  - Personal, alphabetical, Edward Staempfli, 1962-1964 (Box 15, Folder 8-13)
  - Personal, alphabetical, William A. Sutton, 1944-1945 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Personal, alphabetical, Helen Taylor, 1953-1960 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Personal, alphabetical, Joan Temple, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Other personal correspondents, arranged chronologically, 1942-2011 (Box 15, Folder 17-28, Box 16, Folder 1-18, Box 17, Folder 1-21, Box 18, Folder 1-11)
  - Personal correspondence, From envelope marked "Billet Doux", 1964-1975 (Box 18, Folder 12)